字幕整理:皓瀚霏凡
-=圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品=-
HD.CnSCG.Com
-=TLF字幕组 荣誉出品=-
翻译/校对:MiceZhang
这些年来 我有很多的称谓
Through the years, I have been known by many names.
恶魔之猫
Diablo Gato.
毛毛爱人
The Furry Lover.
卓柏卡布拉
Chupacabra.
超级活宝
Friskie Two-Times.
还有活力猛猫
And the Ginger Hit Man.
但大多数人叫我:穿靴子的猫
But to most... I am Puss In Boots!
法外之徒
Outlaw.
永远牵挂你...玛格丽塔
I will never forget you... Margherita.
我是说 罗莎
I mean, Rosa.
抱歉 我想我该走了
Sorry. I think maybe I should go.
我会抓到你的
You cannot run forever,
穿靴子的猫!
Puss In Boots!
这就是我 一只小坏猫
What can I say? I was a bad kitty.
作为通缉犯 逃亡奔走
Just a fugitive from the law... forever running.
试图洗刷罪名
Searching for a way to clear my name.
穿靴子的猫
而今晚
And I would get that chance
上天给了我这个机会
...on this one fateful night.
火焰节
也是鸡肉节
这边 小猫猫
Here, kitty, kitty!
拉乌尔
Raoul.
看它和猫一样窝囊
Look what the cat dragged in.
哦 等等 它本来就是猫
Oh, wait... That is the cat!
一杯牛奶 谢谢
One leche, please.
您来这里有何贵干 先生? 在找毛线团吗?
What are you doing here, senior? Did you lose your ball of yarn?
很好笑
So funny.
牛奶马上来
One leche coming up.
我不想生事
I am not looking for trouble.
我只是一只找寻下一餐的卑微的猫
I am but a humble gato in search of his next meal.
也许各位绅士能给我指条路
Perhaps you gentlemen can help me find a simple score?
你今晚能找到的只有麻烦 穿靴子的猫
The only thing you'll find tonight is trouble... Puss In Boots.
或许我们有人会报官 说你回来了
Well, perhaps if one of us were to tell the law that you are in town,
我们就能平分赏金了
we could split the reward.
你们惹猫生气了
You made the cat angry.
你们不会喜欢猫生气的
You do not want to make the cat angry!
圣米迦勒教堂新建了一个纯金雕像
The Church of St. Michael has just put up a golden statue
圣母瓜达卢佩
of the Virgin of Guadalupe.
我不沾教堂的钱
I do not steal from churches.
有人给孤儿院捐赠了银烛台
The boys' orphanage has been donated silver candlesticks,
它们很适合你家
they would look very lovely in your home.
孤儿院也不是我的菜
I do not steal from orphans.
那杰克和吉尔如何?
Uh, what about Jack and Jill?
- 嘘!你疯啦? - 说下去!
- Shh! Are you crazy? - The what?
在逃杀人犯 杰克和吉尔
The murderous outlaws Jack and Jill
他们手上有魔豆
have gotten their hands on... magic beans.
别拿魔豆和我开玩笑!
Do not joke with me about magic beans!
我找了它们半辈子 它们不存在
I searched half my life for them. They do not exist.
不 猫 我亲眼见过
No, cat. We have seen them.
这些传说中的魔豆
These... are the beans of legend.
它们的蔓藤疯长到达巨人的领地
Grows a vine to the Land of Giants,
还有下金蛋的鹅
and the Golden Goose.
下金蛋的鹅...
The Golden Goose...
抢一颗就够你一生享用了
A heist like this could set you up for life.
你的九个一生
All nine of them.
给他看看金蛋蛋
Show him the golden eggs.
别!
No!
好了 已经看够了
Please, you have shown enough.
你要想死就去杰克和吉尔那里偷吧
Only a cat with a death wish would steal the beans from Jack and Jill.
我想的只是还一笔旧债
The only wish I have is to repay an old debt.
而现在机会来了
And this is my chance.
所以
Now...
杰克和吉尔在哪?
...where do I find this Jack and Jill?
抱歉 没有空房了
I'm sorry... we have no rooms.
我想有人刚退房了
Well, I think one just opened up.
赠送的早餐要欧式的
We'd like a complimentary continental breakfast.
还有别想在小松饼上给我减料
And don't even think about skimpin' on them baby muffins.
人家这里不供应小松饼啊
We don't have any baby muffins.
吉尔 我考虑很久了
You know, Jill, I been thinking.
快说吧
Get it out.
我等魔豆这票干完了
I... Once we're done with this magic bean business
拿到了值钱的金蛋
and got ourselves all them beautiful golden eggs...
然后呢?
Go on.
我们不要再继续抢劫和杀人了
That we cut down on some of the hijacking and murdering.
我知道这样很好玩 但是...
I mean, it's fun and all, but...
我想要个孩子
...I want a baby.
- 什么孩子 杰克? - 我们的孩子 吉尔
- A baby what, Jack? - A baby us, Jill.
我们会把他抚养得很狂野 就像松鼠似的
We'll raise it wild, like a squirrel or something.
我的豆豆啊 它们是真的
Holy frijoles! They do exist.
自打你从山上跌下来摔坏了下巴
Ever since you fell down that hill and broke your crown,
你就开始说胡话了
you have been talking crazy.
嘿 在搞什么?
Hey! What gives?
不! 不! 不!
No! No! No!
你你你 呆在哪儿别动!
You, you, you! You stop where you are!
那些豆子是我的!
Those beans are mine!
我?
Me?
你掐死我?
You snap me?
你掐死我?!
You snap me?!
找什么呢?
You looking for something?
没什么
No.
我不懂鹰语
No hablo ingles.
你要为此付出代价!
You are going to pay for this!
不!
No!
卓柏卡布拉!
Chupacabra!
卓柏卡布拉! 卓柏卡布拉!
Chupacabra! Chupacabra!
- 卓柏卡布拉! - 你脑子被驴踢了!
- Chupacabra! - You are a crazy woman!
这些魔豆是我的猎物
Those magic beans were my score!
你害我失去了得到金蛋的良机 伙计
You just cost me a chance at getting the golden eggs, mi amigo.
伸爪吧
Put up your dukes.
周二之夜 比舞决斗
非常好
Very well.
既然是比舞决斗
If it is to be a dance fight,
那我就在周二之晚的比舞决斗上让你死而无憾
then I will Tuesday-Night-Dance-Fight you to the death!
你胆敢对我作这个动作!
How dare you do the Litter Box at me!
你好啊!
Hello!
感觉到我了么?
Can you feel me?
够胆的话 畏惧我吧
Fear me... if you dare.
你用吉他打我的头?!
You hit me in the head with a guitar?!
你是母猫?
You are a woman?
真不专业
Amateur.
哇!
Wow!
小姐 等等!
Senorita, wait!
能赏脸让我请你喝杯奶吗? 我很有爱 并不暴力
Let me buy you some leche! I am a lover, not a fighter.
有人吗?
Hello?
在和我躲猫猫吗?
You are hiding from me?
我也很喜欢玩游戏哦
I like to play the games, too.
我感觉我们气味相投啊
I sense in you a kindred spirit, a...
这气味很熟悉
I smell something familiar.
闻起来很危险
Something... dangerous.
闻起来像早餐
Something...breakfasty.
很久不见啊 兄弟
It's been a long time, brother.
该死的蛋!
Maldito huevo.
矮蛋・亚历山大
Humpty Alexander Dumpty.
你怎敢出现在我面前
How dare you show your face to me.
我知道你很生气 你应该生气
I know you're angry. You have every right.
但我真的很高兴见到你 猫
But it is good to see you, Puss.
穿的新靴子吗?
Are those new boots?
不! 还是你出卖我时穿的那双
No! They are the same boots I wore when you betrayed me.
背叛你?
Betrayed you?
你留下心碎的我在那座桥上 还被卫兵围捕
You left me cracked in pieces on a bridge, surrounded by soldiers!
他们还为此写了首歌
They wrote a song about it!
那我们是为什么会到那座桥上的?!
And how did we get on that bridge in the first place?!
因为我们是兄弟 而兄弟就应该互相照顾对方
Because we were brothers, and brothers are supposed to look after each other...
矮蛋!
Humpty!
不要把正事忘了
Remember why we're here.
我早该料到
I should have known.
魔豆当时已经在我掌控中
I had the magic beans in my grasp,
而你派这只小魅魔来干涉我
and you sent this very attractive devil woman to interfere.
你就是我一生的诅咒
You are a curse on my life!
等等 听我说完 好吗?
Wait. Hear me out. OK?
对 没错 我让咪咪带你来这里
Yes, yes, I sent Kitty to bring you here.
但她不是一般的窃贼
But she is no ordinary thief.
她是咪・柔爪
She's Kitty Softpaws.
有全西班牙最柔软的爪子
The softest touch in Spain.
男的穿这样高的根不舒服吧 不是吗?
That's a lot of heel for a guy, don't you think?
听好 有着咪的手段 你的剑术和我的头脑
Look, with Kitty's skill, your sword and my brain,
我们有了千载难逢的机会啊
we've got a fighting chance here.
猫 拜托 你们都知道没人能从
Puss, come on, you of all people know that nobody's ever ripped off
巨人的城堡里偷走东西还能活着回来的
the giant's castle and lived to tell the tale.
你想全身而退 就得有计划
You want to survive? You need a plan.
而我一生都在计划这件事 你知道的
And I've studied this job my whole life. You know that.
我们真诚相待
Let's be honest.
没有我你也不知道在哪里种魔豆 猫
Without me, you don't even know where to plant the beans, Puss.
但杰克和吉尔知道 他们已经启程了
But Jack and Jill do. They're on their way.
通缉犯爬上豆茎 下来就成了传奇
We go up the beanstalk outlaws, and we come down legends.
你意见如何?
So what do you say?
伙计?
Partners?
不 我不会再上当
No. Never again.
对不起 好没? 你这仇要记恨多久啊?
I'm sorry, OK? How long are you gonna hold a grudge?
都七年了! 差不多三十五个猫年了
It's been seven years! That's like 35 cat years.
你需要我! 而且我需要你
You need me! And I need you.
猫! 你知道在圣里卡多的监狱里 他们怎么对蛋的吗?
Puss! You got any idea what they do to eggs in San Ricardo prison?
我来告诉你 朋友
I'll tell you this, my friend.
可不像煎蛋那么简单
It ain't over easy.
再见 矮蛋!
Adios... Humpty Dumpty.
哦 糟糕了 糟糕了
Oh, this is bad. This is bad.
别担心 我来对付他 我也是只猫猫哦
Don't worry, I'll take care of it. I know how to speak meow.
你用扭曲的谎言编造出悲惨的故事
...sad story with your twisted lies
还有你那油腻腻的蛋壳 闻起来像发霉的火腿!
in your greasy shell that smells like old ham!
我该当场把你敲碎!
I should crack you open for...
看看我找到啥了
Look what I found.
有人忘记拿钱包哦
Someone forgot his money.
哦 你真是很危险
Oh, you are dangerous.
矮蛋说你喜欢冒险
Humpty says you like danger.
想想看 我们会遇到的危险
Just think of all the trouble we can get into.
我们俩 一起
The two of us together.
我们能拿到不少的金蛋
We can steal a lot of golden eggs.
而且...你欠我的
And... you owe me.
我欠你啥?
I owe you?
你用吉他打了我
You hit me in the head with a guitar.
吉他很后悔
I regret the guitar.
好吧 我原谅你
OK, I forgive you.
那你加入吗?
So... you're in?
只有一个很小的微不足道的小问题
There is one teeny, tiny, itty-bitty problem.
是什么呢?
And what is that?
你的老板是矮蛋!
You work for the egg!
拜托啊 猫 你和矮蛋之间到底发生了什么天大的事?
Oh, come on, Puss. What happened between you and Humpty that was so bad?
恐怕我们俩之间伤痕太深了
I am afraid with me and Humpty... the scars are too deep.
那是多年前的事情了
It all started a long time ago.
不! 你大可不必把整件事情都说完
Oh, no. You really don't have to tell me your whole life story, please.
请坐下 我详说
You may want to sit.
那是一段悲痛的日子
It is at times quite... painful.
好吧 开始了
OK, here we go.
那是闹旱灾的一年
It was a year in which the rain had not fallen.
大风呼啸 猫篮羸小
The wind was big and the basket was small.
随风颠簸 饥寒难消
For days, I bounced along...
没有妈妈 没有酒吧
...a hungry little kitten with no milk, no mama,
没有24小时奶喝的家
and no litter box.
直到我来到一个收留孤儿的地方
Until I came to rest at a home for lost children.
她的名字是伊梅尔达
Her name was Imelda.
如同母亲一般用心对待我 如同亲生儿子一般
And, like a mother, she took me into her heart and raised me as her own.
都安静
Silencio.
安静
她像天使般的温柔善良
She was an angel of kindness.
安静!
Silencio!
大多数时候吧
Most of the time.
我要给大家介绍一个新来的同学
I'd like to introduce a new boy joining us.
没事的 孩子 和大家见见面吧
It's OK, pequeno. You show with the face.
去吧
Go on.
就是那时我认识了...
And that was the moment I met...
矮蛋・亚历山大
Humpty Alexander Dumpty.
长毛的 你坐在了蓝小子的座位上
Hey, Whiskers! You're sitting in Little Boy Blue's chair.
哦 拜托 这有必要吗?
Oh, come on. Is this necessary?
怎么不找个和你一样块头的欺负?
Why don't you pick on somebody your own size?
谁问你了 早餐?
Who asked you, Breakfast?
还记得伊美尔达怎么说的吗 蓝小子?
Remember what Imelda says, Boy Blue
如果你怒发冲天 就用力吹你的号角 不是吗?
If you're going to blow your top, you blow your horn instead, right?
我们来玩转蛋蛋吧
Let's spin him.
请别转我 不要转我!
Please don't spin me. Do not spin me!
不要再转了! 不要! 我会散黄的!
Not again! No! I'm gonna yolk!
虽然他拿了我的豆子 但他为我挺身而出
Even though he took my beans, the egg stood up for me,
那时我就决定了
and I decided then...
我要永远保护他
...that I would always have his back.
哇哦!
Wow!
你真是太厉害了 谢谢
That was very impressive. Thanks!
蛋蛋男!
Hey, egg boy!
但这只奇怪的蛋总是让我好奇
There was something about this strange little egg that intrigued me.
是你啊 我收集豆子都好几个月了
Oh... it's you. I've been collecting for months now.
你总不知道运气什么时候来 明白吗?
You never know when you're gonna get lucky. You know what I mean?
魔豆 就是我要找的
Magic beans... is what they are.
喂?
Hello?
你要向其他的孩子说我相信魔法吗?
You gonna tell all the other kids that I believe in magic now?
你正打算这样吗?
Is that what you're gonna do?
不吗? 你叫什么名字?
No? What's your name?
你不怎么说话 对吧?
You don't say much, do you?
我觉得就叫你闪闪
I think I'll call you Sparky.
毛毛?
Whiskers?
索尔塔!
Zoltar!
那叫"猫"怎么样?
How about Puss?
他脑子里都是各种的幻想和冒险
Humpty's mind was full of imagination and invention.
那边十五尺高的那是什么?
What is that, 50 feet down there?
这就来吧 帮我...
Here we go. Give me a...
猫!
Puss!
猫 快看我 我在飞!
Look at me, Puss! I'm flying!
他总是说着超乎我想象的传说和冒险
He spoke of legends and adventures beyond my wildest dreams.
当我找到那些魔法豆后
When I find those magic beans, they'll grow a vine
让它们长到云里
straight up into the clouds,
在那里有着可怕残忍的巨人 守护他最宝贵的宝藏
where a terrible and a fearsome giant hoards his greatest treasure...
黄金之鹅
...the Golden Goose.
黄金鹅 只要一颗
Oh, the Golden Goose. Just one.
只要一颗她产下的金蛋 就够我一生享用了
Just one of her golden eggs... could set me for life.
这是我的使命 猫
It's my destiny, Puss.
我不知道怎么解释 但我总觉得我属于那里的世界
I can't really explain it, but I just feel like I belong up there.
哦 小子 这有些难为情
Oh, boy. This is awkward.
这只是我个人的梦想
This is kind of a solo dream here.
我的确不需要什么累赘 知道吗? 拖后腿的人
I don't need any dead weight, you know, holding me down.
你这是干什么?
What are you doing?
我的天 太棒了 你眼睛的把戏 实在太棒了
Oh, man, that's good. The eye thing that you're doing, that is really splendid.
好了 让我再想一想 好吗?
OK, let me just think for a second. All right... OK.
这太疯狂了 但我在想...想要一个搭档
This is crazy, but I am considering a partnership.
但我还要知道一件事
I just need to know one thing.
你能保证吗?
Can you commit?
好 我能保证
Si... I can commit.
你能说话啊 能帮我起来吗?
Oh, you can talk! Could you help me up?
没问题
OK...
魔豆帮帮规第一条
First rule of Bean Club...
不能谈起魔豆帮
...you do not talk about Bean Club.
魔豆帮帮规第二条
Second rule of Bean Club...
还是不能谈起魔豆帮
...is you don't talk about Bean Club.
- 准备好了? - 好了
- You ready? - Ready.
从今天开始到永远 我们会
From this day forth, it shall be known...
永不落单 团结一致
Never alone, always together...
矮蛋和猫
Humpty and Puss...
永是兄弟
Brothers forever.
从那时起
And from that moment on,
我们一起展开了伟大的冒险:寻找魔豆
we were united on a great adventure to find the magic beans.
扶我
Help me up.
贴蛋
Egg me.
矮蛋就是主脑
Humpty was the brains...
- 我的天啊! - 我根本没看到他
- Good gracious! - I never saw him!
- 真的好疼啊! - 而我就是执行者
- That really hurt! - ...and I was the skill.
我要碎了!
I'm cracked!
我们得到了红豆 绿豆 咖啡豆和利马豆...但没有魔豆
We got red beans, green beans, coffee beans, lima beans... but no magic beans.
要果冻豆吗?
Would you care for a jelly bean?
要 谢谢
Thank you.
寻找魔豆就是我们的一切
Finding them meant everything to us.
哦 我差点忘了最重要的哦
Oh, I almost forgot the most important thing.
那就是我和你 猫
That's me and you, Puss.
我和你
Me and you.
但我们从没找到
But we never did find them.
一年一年过去了 寻找魔豆的任务
And, as years passed, the quest for magic beans
越来越像孩子的梦想了
seemed more and more like the dreams of a child.
青年时 矮蛋和我总是惹事...
As teenagers, Humpty and I looked for trouble...
而结果就是
and often found it.
这个月第三次了 伊梅尔达 下一次我直接送监狱了
Third time this month, Imelda. Next time is jail time.
他们还是孩子啊
They're just kids.
他们是小偷!
They are thieves.
你们能有更大的作为
You are better than this.
我一直从心里相信这点
I believe in you with all my heart.
请不要让我失望
Please do not let me down.
我讨厌这地方 我等不及要离开这里了
I hate this place. I cannot wait for us to get out of here.
扔石头吧 能让你好受些
Throw a rock. It'll make you feel better.
天啊 该走了
Oh, boy. We should go.
出于本能 我行动了
On instinct, I reacted.
他救了卫队长的妈妈
He saved the Comandante's mother!
他救了卫
队长的妈妈
你救了我妈妈
You saved my mother.
猫先生...他是位英雄!
Senor Puss... he is a hero!
今天我们看到了勇气和胆量
Today we see that courage and bravery come in all sizes!
那时我也不知道 我的人生在那时起就改变了
Little did I know that one moment would change my whole life.
这是给你的 我的孩子
These are for you, my boy.
穿上它们 代表着荣誉和正义
Wear them as a symbol of honor... and justice.
我会让你骄傲的 妈妈
I will make you proud, Mama.
你已经让我骄傲了 穿靴子的猫
You already have, my Puss In Boots.
一只猫穿靴子有多奇怪啊
How strange it was to give a cat boots...
但我看起来真帅
...but, whoa... I looked good!
当我的人生路越来越明亮时
And as the light of my path grew brighter...
而他的人生路却越来越阴暗
...Humpty's road grew ever darker.
谢谢你 卫队长
Gracias, Comandante.
小心选择你的伙伴
Be careful of the company you keep.
我知道 我知道我不该独自行动
I know! I know, I never should've tried something without you.
你不能再去偷棒棒糖了 矮蛋 我是说真的
You're not stealing lollipops any more, Humpty. This is getting serious.
你说的对 我们应该做更精明的事
You're right! We have to be smarter about this.
听我说 我们要想得更远大
Here, look. We need to think bigger.
我已经侦查过银匠铺了 很完美
I've been casing the silversmith and it's perfect.
你和我只需要不到一分钟就完事
You and me, in and out, 50 seconds tops.
快把本子收起来! 这是我们家
Will you put that away! This is our home.
这些人没做过任何对不起我们的事
These people have done nothing to us.
我们家? 好了 我明白了
Our home? OK, yeah, I get it now.
你有了双好靴子 你就比我强了?
You get some fancy boots and now you're too good for me?
不是那么回事
That is not true.
我们不在这儿出生 我们是孤儿
We weren't born here. We're orphans!
我们只能相依为命 明白吗?
All we got is each other, you understand?
我们能更有作为
We are better than this.
但我们是搭档啊
But we're partners.
我们是兄弟
We are brothers.
但我不会再偷东西了
But I am not stealing anymore.
但矮蛋却没那么容易放弃
But Humpty would not give up so easily.
我有麻烦了 猫
I'm in trouble, Puss!
是蓝小子的一个混混 我欠他一笔钱
It's Boy Blue and his gang. I owe them some money.
他们要来找我了 快帮我翻过这道墙
They're coming for me. Just get me over this wall.
我们快走! 帮我翻墙 快点!
I gotta go. Help me up the wall. Get me up the wall. Hurry! Hurry!
圣里卡多银行
好了 东西拿齐了 成功了 快走 走!
OK, I've got everything. We did it. Come on, let's go!
你怎么能这样对我?!
How could you do this to me?!
我帮了你大忙啊 我们终于可以离开这里了
I did you a favor! We can finally get out of here!
这可是大家的钱啊 是他们所有的积蓄
This is the money of the people! This is all they have!
你!让这双靴子蒙羞!
You disgrace those boots!
卫队长!求求你 让我解释
Comandante, please, I can explain!
抓住他们!
Arrest them!
快! 到桥那儿!
Hurry up! Get to the bridge!
- 你骗我! - 我必须骗你 你让我别无选择
- You tricked me! - I had to! You left me no choice!
妈妈
Mama...
我的孩子
Pequeno.
看路!
Watch out!
哦 不
Oh, no.
猫 我起不来
Puss. I can't get up.
帮帮我 我起不来
Puss! Help me. I can't get up!
站住!
Freeze!
猫 救救我!
Puss, save me!
自己救自己吧
Save yourself.
我们需要你
We got you.
在那一天 我失去了我在乎的一切
I lost everything I cared about that day.
我的兄弟
My brother.
我的荣誉
My honor.
我的家
My home.
我能想到的是 妈妈眼里深深的失望
All I thought about was the disappointment in my mama's eyes.
从那时起我就在逃亡
And I have been running ever since.
那颗蛋背叛了我
The egg betrayed me.
他的谎言 让我失去一切
His lies cost me everything.
- 嘿! - 我没睡!
- Hey! - I'm awake!
你以为我不想弥补过去吗?
You think I don't want to fix the past?
我下不来
I can't get down.
听好 没有一天
Listen. A day... A day doesn't go by
我不想我失去的东西
when I don't think about what I lost.
我失去了最好的朋友
I lost my best friend.
我唯一的朋友
My only friend.
而我明白了 我曾变得贪婪 穷凶极恶 让人失望
And I get it now. I got greedy and desperate and I let you down.
让自己失望
I let myself down.
我唯一想要的是 猫 再给我一次机会
All I'm asking for, Puss, is a second chance.
再给我一次机会 我就能补偿圣里卡多
Give me that second chance and I'll help you pay back San Ricardo.
求求你 猫
Please, Puss.
让我向你证明 我们的友情对我有多重要
Let me show you what our friendship meant to me.
- 我加入 - 太好了
- I will do it. - that's great.
我加入 是为了妈妈和圣里卡多 而不是你
I will do this for my mother and for San Ricardo... not for you.
我们不是搭档 也不是朋友
We are not partners and we are not friends.
好 我向你保证 不会再让你失望了
OK. I promise this time, I will not let you down.
好!
Yes!
我想我们的魔豆帮重组了
I think we got our Bean Club back.
蛋蛋的计划能成功
Humpty's plan better work.
听好 你只需要关心你的任务 别砸锅了
Listen, you just need to worry about your part. Don't screw it up.
- 怎么? - 又要戴面具?
- What? - Again with the mask?
我才不用尘灰靴先生给我造型意见
I don't need style advice from Mr. Dusty Boots.
加油 猫 快!
Come on, Puss. Now!
我们的年级也不小了 亲爱的
Our biological clocks are tickin', darlin'.
- 我们该为未来着想了 - 你怎么搞的?
- You gotta look at the big picture. - What's your problem?
听好 我一直都有努力保养
Listen. I put a lot of work into my body.
我看起来很好 而我也不会让这些努力付诸东流
I look good, and I am not just gonna throw that away.
- 怎么了? - 瞧
- What? - Look.
让我们假装你有一个孩子
Let's just pretend you have a baby.
太完美了
Excellent.
我才没有时间在家里洗尿片和袜子
I don't have time to be at home with no diapers and baby socks.
你大可不必 我可以作住家爸爸
You don't have to, Jill. I'll be the stay-at-home dad.
我们后面就有十只饥饿的小猪
We got ten hungry piggies, there in the back.
你可以先用它们练习 就停车然后喂饱它们
You can practice on them. Just pull over, feed them.
动作快一些
You've got to hurry up.
他是一个可爱的小家伙
He's a cute little bugger.
怎么不用你的爪子?
Why are you not using your claws?
能给我闭嘴吗? 我在弄了
Would you please just shut up! I'm on it!
快用你的爪子! - 给我安静!
- Just use your claws! - Be quiet.
你的爪子! - 我没有爪子 好吗?!
- Your claws! - I don't have any claws, all right?!
是小猪在叫吗?
Was that Hamhock?
好了好了 小猪乖 快睡觉哈
There, there. Sleepy, sleepy, big, fat piggy.
照顾小猪
You babysit.
柔爪
- Soft paws.
好没?
Well?
你好 传说中的豆子
Hello, beans of legend.
我们走
Let's go.
看看谁来了 吉尔
Well, well, well. Look what we have here, Jill.
你敢动我们的宝宝
You messed with our baby.
你还偷了我的魔豆
And you took my beans.
炸弹香肠来了!
Sausage bomb!
你们会付出代价! 坏猫!
You're gonna pay for this! Soul-sucking cats!
给蛋发信号
Signal the egg!
好!
Yes!
- 好了 - 准备
- OK. - Ready.
- 预备 - 跳!
- Set. - Go!
哦 天呐!
Oh, my God!
好了 小猫 把豆子给我吧
All right, cat. Give me them beans.
猫真的总是用脚着地吗?
Is it true a cat always lands on its feet?
不! 那只是狗散播的谣言!
No! That is just a rumor spread by dogs!
那就让我们看看
Well, let's find out.
看见了吗? 我说过不会让你失望吧
See? I told you I wouldn't let you down!
你以为就这样完了?
You think this is over?
差点打中我了!
Hey, that was close!
现在!
Now!
我们一定要撑到桥边! 坐好了!
We just got to make it to that bridge! Hang on!
- 矮蛋 那里没有桥! - 相信我
- Humpty! There is no bridge! - Trust me.
矮蛋!
Humpty!
我们死定啦!
We're going to die!
我恨猫
I hate cats.
我们没完!
This is war!
巨人的城堡
Giant's castle...
我们来了
...here we come.
我得把魔豆交给矮蛋
I must hand it to the egg.
这是团队的成果 矮蛋依然有爪子
This was a team effort. Humpty still has his claws...
我是说连手 这才是我想说的 不是爪子 他也不是猫
I mean, flaws. That was what I meant, not claws. He's not a cat.
- 我没觉得这样有什么问题 - 我不想谈这个
- Not to say there's anything wrong... - I don't want to talk about it.
明白
Got it.
好了 我们就要到了
OK, we should be close!
留意所有运动不寻常的云
Keep your eyes out for any strange cloud activity!
我被称之为咪・柔爪 是因为我能偷走你的东西
I am called Kitty Softpaws because I'll steal you blind
而你却完全没有察觉
and you'll never even know I was there.
咪?
Kitty?
你和他们说的不一样
You are not as good as they say.
比传说更好
You're better.
我会尊重你的隐私
I will respect your privacy.
好吧 和你说吧
OK. I'll tell you.
那时我只是流浪猫
I was just a stray...
我有很美的爪子
but I had beautiful claws.
有天 一对善良的夫妇收养了我
One day, a really nice couple took me in.
每天早上给我牛奶喝
Gave me milk every morning.
爱着我
Loved me.
或许是我玩地毯玩太过了 或者对仓鼠太不友善
Maybe I scratched their curtains or played too rough with the hamster.
我不知道他们为什么这样
I don't know why they did it.
他们拔了我的爪子
But they took my claws.
爱猫的人都是疯子
Cat people are crazy.
快停车!我想我们到了
Stop the coach! I think this is it!
你能相信吗 猫?
Can you believe this, Puss?
猫?这么多年之后
After all these years!
来 我想让你来种
Here. I want you to plant them.
这块云的确奇怪
That... is a strange cloud.
好 就是它了! 这都是真的 快来!
OK! This is it! It's happening, hurry!
这边来
This Way!
很好 走快点 走快点
Good, good. Come on, come on, come on.
二十三除以云的厚度
Twenty-three divided by cloud depth.
停! 就这里!
Hole! Right here.
现在 种下豆子
Now place the beans.
请小心地种下豆子
Place the beans carefully, please.
不要叠在一起 这些魔法很娇弱
Not on top of each other. The magic is very delicate.
好了 非常好 现在 我们后退
OK, good. Very good. Now just stand back.
这是怎么回事?
What's happening here?
是不是魔法在你口袋里走光了?
Maybe the magic rubbed off in your pocket?
- 不可能 - 好了 好了 不要恐慌
- That's impossible. - OK, OK. Let's not panic.
知道吗 我从书上读过 植物也有感觉的
You know, I read somewhere that plants have feelings.
所以...过去对它说些好话
So, come on... say something nice to it.
好
OK.
让我想一想
Let me just think for a second.
嗨 小豆芽
Hi, little plant.
伙计们
Guys?
矮蛋!
Humpty!
- 我看不到他了 你看到没? - 我也找不到他
- I do not see him. Do you see him? - I don't see him anywhere.
你声音好怪
You sound weird.
因为空气稀薄
It's the thin air!
快下来 感觉太棒了
Come on in! It feels great!
这些云在挠我的鼻子
The cloud, it tickles my nose.
那是因为这些水气 天晓得呢
That's because they effervesce! Who knew?
来吧
Come on.
抓到了!
Gotcha!
喵...
Meow.
猫 觉得如何? 我该剃胡子吗?
Hey, Puss. What do you think? Do I shave?
来给你看样东西
Let me show you something.
这下面某个地方 有两个孩子
Somewhere down there, there are two little kids,
不知道是不是孤儿呢
I don't know, maybe orphans,
他们躺在草地上看云
and they're laying on a hill, staring at the clouds,
梦想着未来
dreaming about the future.
就是我和你 猫
That was me and you, Puss.
我和你
Me and you.
小子们
Boys!
们应该看看这个
You might want to take a look at this.
巨人的城堡
The giant's castle.
好了 该整装了
OK, time to suit up.
矮蛋!
Humpty!
我会完美地和金蛋混在一起
I'll fit right in with the golden eggs.
很棒吧 嗯?
Brilliant or what, huh?
矮蛋 你没穿内裤
Humpty, you're not wearing underwear!
怎么? 你感到难为情? 我没有哦
What? Are you embarrassed? I'm not.
猫 还记得别人都笑话魔豆帮吗?
Puss, remember when everyone was laughing at Bean Club?
现在是谁笑得出来? 我们!
And who is laughing now? We are!
哇
Wow!
那就是我们的目标
That is our target.
我们说话不像人妖了
Hey, you don't sound like an elf anymore.
因为这里面的气压正常了
It's because the air pressure in here is normal.
我们走
Let's go.
计划是这样:你们去拿走金蛋 我去找巨人单挑
So here is the plan: You two get the golden eggs, I will fight the giant.
没有巨人和你单挑 巨人死了好几年了
There's no giant to fight. The giant's been dead for years.
- 什么? - 你不怎么读书 对吧?
- What?! - You didn't do the reading, did you?
《杰克与魔豆》第14章里 "巨人永远长眠了"
Jack and the Beanstalk, chapter 14, "Giant Takes a Big Dirt Nap."
脚跟疼
Ankle burn.
- 那是什么? - 这就是他们说的"恐怖"
- What was that? - They call it the Great Terror.
守护黄金之鹅的那只怪物
It's the monster that guards the Golden Goose.
传说中提到过 当你直视它 你就会变成石头
Legend has it that if you look at it, you'll turn to stone.
没有人能证实 是因为没人能活着逃脱它
But nobody really knows because nobody's walked away from it alive.
跟着我 别作声
Follow me and keep quiet.
嘘!矮蛋!
Shh! Humpty!
我忍不住啊 我全身都粘粘痒痒的
I can't help it. Everything's rubbing and pinching!
我得用爽身粉
I need powder!
我们要怎么过去?
How are we gonna get across?
开香槟
Champagne.
干杯!
Cheers!
别害怕哦 我会保护你
Do not worry. I will protect you.
你要怎么做? 用吉他敲它的头?
What are you gonna do? Hit it in the head with a guitar?
拜托 别再提吉他的事
Please. Stop bringing up the guitar.
接住我!
Catch me!
快!
Hurry!
躲!
Hide!
别看它!
Don't look at it!
矮蛋 闭嘴!
Humpty! Be quiet!
我说我不能呼吸 你还堵住我的嘴！
I said I couldn't breathe and then you zipped the thing over my mouth!
你得振作起来 加油!
You gotta get it together. Come on!
好
OK.
看看啊 就像蛋蛋天堂
Look at this. It's egg paradise.
这儿太美了 我觉得我就属于这里
It's so beautiful, I feel like I belong here.
金蛋!
Golden eggs.
尽你所能享受吧
Grab as many as you can.
我还以为它们和鸡蛋一样大
I thought they were going to be like chicken size.
你能想象它怎么下金蛋的吗? 矮油
Can you imagine laying one of these? Ouch!
猫!
Puss!
我们要怎么把蛋弄出去?
How are we supposed to get these out of here?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我的天啊
Oh, my!
黄金之鹅
The Golden Goose.
看看她啊 她不美吗?
Just look at her. Isn't she beautiful?
我亲爱的宝贝
My sweet darling.
我觉得她喜欢你
I think she likes you.
我们就带走她吧
Let's just take her.
等等 这可是传说中的鹅啊
Wait a minute. This is the goose of legend.
我们不知道带走她会有什么后果
We don't know what happens if we take her.
我知道不带走她会有什么后果 我们啥也没捞着
I know what happens if we don't take her, we got nothing.
大家伙 她能下金子啊 我们要带走她
Guys, guys. It's a gold peeper. We're taking it!
就快到了
Almost there!
抓稳!
Hang on!
坚持一下!
它来了!
It's coming!
跑!
Run!
咪!
Kitty!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
抓稳!
Hang on!
给我过来!
Come here, you.
抓到你了!
Got you!
她是我的了
She's mine now!
你好
Hello!
不!飞啊 小鹅 飞啊!
Oh, no! Fly, little gosling, fly!
不! 不应该是这个样子的!
No! It's not supposed to be this way!
- 猫? - 不是
- Puss? - No.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢谢 威猛先生
Thanks, Ginger.
我们应该砍了那豆芽
We should maybe cut that down.
看啊 你终于有了想要的家庭了 杰克
Look at that. You finally got that family you wanted, Jack.
听到了吗? 我想他刚才叫我"爸爸"了
Did you hear that? I think he just called me Daddy.
- 他看起来很像你 杰克 - 谢谢
- He looks just like you, Jack. - Thank you.
矮蛋
那是什么?
Well, what is it?
我相信这是给我们的信号
I do believe that's our cue.
为了报答圣里卡多!
To paying back San Ricardo!
为了富有
To being rich!
棒极了
iOle?
你
You.
我?
Me?
嗯嗯 宝贝
Yeah, yeah, baby!
一 二 恰恰恰
One, two, cha-cha-cha!
三 四 恰恰恰
Three, four, cha-cha-cha!
一 二... 什么?!
One, two... What?!
我只有一个字对你说 咪・柔爪 喵...
There is one word for you, Kitty Softpaws: Me-wow!
我知道你很有女人缘 超级猛猫先生
I know you have quite a reputation with the ladies, Mr. Friskie Two-Times.
我同时也被称为 毛毛爱人
I've also been known as the... Furry Lover!
但那都是认识你之前的事了
But that was before I met you.
但你不认识我 猫 我不是你想象中的那样
You don't know me, Puss. I'm not who you think I am. I'm all about the score.
来吧 看着我的眼睛 告诉我你只在乎那些金子
Come on. Look me in the eyes and tell me all you care about is the gold.
- 猫... - 咪...
- Puss... - Kitty...
哦 天啊!
Oh, my God!
交换舞伴
New partners!
不要被他的公猫魅力迷惑 要专注
Do not fall for his animal magnetism. You stay focused.
什么?!
What?!
我一直在想 柔爪小姐
So... I have been thinking, Miss Softpaws,
如果我们要分开走的话 那我们就能一起分开走了
that when we go our separate ways, we can go our separate ways...together.
猫 你必须要走了
Puss, you have to go, now.
你不必再抗拒我了 请相信我
You do not have to push me away any more. You can trust me
为圣里卡多的传奇喝彩吧 矮蛋和猫 我们成功了
Give it up for the legends of San Ricardo, Humpty and Puss! We did it!
- 我先去睡了 大家伙 - 咪 一起庆祝吧
- I'm calling it a night, guys. - Kitty! Stay up with us.
不了 我感觉...要吐毛球了
No, I feel a... hairball coming on.
好吧 吐得开心点
OK, yeah. Have fun with that!
我们该给她一点私人空间
We should give her some privacy.
我从没想到我们能走到这一步
I never thought we would get to here.
在经历过这些事之后 能把它们都抛诸脑后
After all we went through to pull this off, together.
和好兄弟重聚的感觉真好
It is good to have my brother back.
是啊 的确是
Yep. Sure is.
明天可有好戏上演
Well, we have a big day tomorrow.
多让人兴奋啊
Pretty exciting stuff.
我们该休息了
We should get some rest.
晚安 矮蛋
Good night, Humpty.
我还没死
I am still alive!
杰克和吉尔
Jack and Jill.
咪?
Kitty?
矮蛋?
Humpty?
我会找到你们的
I will find you.
快给我滚!
Get out of here!
圣里卡多
通缉:穿靴子的猫 赏钱500
走开!
Be gone!
你想要什么? 金子吗? 我有金子啊
What do you want? Gold? I have gold!
杰克 蛋蛋想收买我们呢
Jack, egg's trying to bribe us.
用我们的金子吗
With our own gold.
好了 我们只想吃早餐而已
Come on now, all we want is a little breakfast.
- 不要!求求你! - 你喜欢你的蛋吗 矮蛋?
- No, no, please! - How do you like your eggs, pumpkin?
矮蛋 不!
Humpty, no!
好啊 猫
Hello, Puss.
惊喜哦!
Surprise!
这怎么回事?
What is going on?
这是个惊喜派对啊 而惊喜是给你的
It's a surprise party, and the surprise is on you.
看起来猫猫刚起床呢
Looks like the cat's out of the bag.
你们是一伙的?!
You were in cahoots?!
是啊 他们都为我卖命
Oh, yeah! They all work for me.
我在监狱里为了今天准备了很久
I spent a lot of time in prison preparing for this.
- 你算计我 - 对啊 我算计你了 必须的
- You set me up. - Oh, yeah, I set you up. Of course.
你以为这就是拿回金子 然后挽回你的名声?
You think this was all about getting the gold and clearing your name?
这次的冒险只有一个目的
This little adventure was about one thing.
复仇!
Revenge.
你根本不知道 猫 我一直在你身边
You never knew it, Puss... but I was always there.
你想要补偿过去的过失吗 猫? 我也想
You wanted to repay an old debt, Puss? Well, so did I.
那你为什么这么做?
Why would you do this?
你把我抛弃在了桥上!
You left me on that bridge!
你在我最需要你的时候抛弃了我
You abandoned me when I needed you the most.
- 你忘了"永是兄弟"了?! - 你欺骗了我!
- What happened to "brothers forever"?! - I trusted you!
那你终于明白我的感受了
Well, now you're finally gonna know what it feels like,
就是 当你信赖一个人 他却在你背后插刀
you know, to trust someone and have them stab you in the back.
卫兵!
Guards!
穿靴子的猫 你因打劫圣里卡多银行的罪名而被捕
Puss In Boots, you're under arrest for the robbery of the San Ricardo Bank!
把这当成魔豆帮的最后一次聚头吧
Consider this the final meeting of Bean Club.
我应该把你煎了拌着洋葱吃!
I should scramble you with onions!
你不应该回来这里
You should never have come back.
我的孩子! 等等
iPequeno! Wait.
别和他们打 求你了
Do not fight them, please.
妈妈 听我说 我能解释
Mama! Listen to me. I can explain.
不 猫 别再逃跑了
No. Puss, no more running.
请不要再让我伤心了 面对你做过的一切吧
Please stop breaking my heart and face what you have done.
对不起 妈妈
I'm sorry, Mama.
我让你失望了
I let you down.
把爪子举起来
Paws where we can see them!
转过身 慢慢地
Turn around... slow.
再慢点!
Slower!
走进笼子里 走得安静漂亮些
Step into the carrier... quiet-like.
注意了!注意了! 请大家尽量走近一些
Attention! Attention, everyone! If you could just come in a little closer.
女士们先生们 我为您呈现――传说中的黄金之鹅
Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you... the Golden Goose of legend!
咪 不要是你啊
Kitty. Not you, too?
大家都有金子!
Gold for everyone!
我们有新鲜热辣的金子啦 乡亲们!
We got some fresh, hot gold here, people!
都来拿啊! 要趁热啊!
Step right up! Get it hot!
帽子一顶
One hat.
腰带一条
One belt.
还有一双鞋
And two boots...
曾经 荣耀的象征
...once a symbol of honor.
还有一瓶蒙汗药?
One bottle of catnip?
给我的青光眼用的
It is for my glaucoma.
这就是你该呆的地方 法外之徒
This is where you belong, outlaw.
这就是你度过下半辈子的地方
And this is where you will stay... forever.
别因为我停下来哦
No, no. Don't stop on my account.
看来那颗蛋得到了他想要的东西
Well, it looks like the egg got what he wanted.
你是在说矮蛋吗?
You're talking about Humpty?
别提他的名字 以前那坏蛋和我一起在这个牢房里
Don't say his name! I used to share this cell with that smelly thing.
他离开那天是我人生最快乐的日子
Happiest day of my life was when he left.
直到我发现他偷走了我的魔豆
Till I realized he stole my magic beans.
停停停 你曾拥有魔豆? 你是谁?
Wait, wait, wait! You had the beans? Who are you?
你叫什么名字?
Hey! What's your name?
安迪・豆茎
Andy Beanstalk!
友们都叫我杰克
My friends call me Jack.
我用家里的牛换了那些魔豆
I traded the family cow for them beans.
当然 那不是我家的牛
Course'n, it wasn't my family's cow.
是人家家里的牛 所以我被判了八到十年
It was some other family's family cow. That's why I got eight to ten.
一定要认清楚自己的牛啊
Always know which cow is yours.
老疯子 醒醒!
Crazy man. Wake up!
你还知道什么?
What else do you know?
我们都完了 多亏了那坏蛋
We're all goners, thanks to that little stinky!
我说过不要带走那只鹅 但他一心只想要报仇
I told him not to take the goose, but all he wanted was his revenge!
别带走鹅 为什么?
Don't take the goose. Why?
那个"恐怖" 是黄金之鹅的妈妈
The Great Terror! That's the Golden Goose's mama.
哦 不
Oh, no.
当她回来找寻孩子的时候
And she will be out for blood
就会带来血雨腥风
when she comes back for her baby.
守卫! 圣里卡多灾难临头啦! 你一定要听我说!
Guard! San Ricardo is in terrible danger! You must listen to me!
闭嘴!
Quiet, you!
Shut up.
把门打开
Open the door.
放下武器
Drop the weapon.
很好
Very good.
站一边去
Step aside.
不
No.
恶魔之猫!
Diablo Gato!
有一套嘛
Nice try.
希望你能原谅我
I hope you can forgive me.
道歉接受!
Apology accepted!
我才没有时间理你
I don't really have time for you.
我要保护镇子不被"恐怖"毁了
I have to save the town from the Great Terror!
等等 猫
Wait, Puss!
你不明白吗? 我来这里是因为...
Don't you see? I'm here because...
我来这里是因为你让我明白
I am here because you made me realize
我心里有比金子还重要的东西
that there is something I care about more than gold.
东西?
Something?
好啦 某猫
OK. Someone.
他大概两尺高 穿高跟鞋
He's about two feet tall, wears high heels.
他帅不?
Handsome?
他超级的帅
He's very handsome.
是只猛猫吗?
A real beefcake?
- 骏马? - 是的
- A stallion? - Yes.
- 猛虎? - 大哥...
- Tiger? - Oh, brother.
但是 这并不代表我们扯平了
But this does not make us even.
别动!
Freeze!
不 扯平了
Yes, it does.
不不不 没扯平
No, no, no, it doesn't.
我救过你
I saved you!
你欠我一次
You owed me one.
你没告诉我矮蛋的计划
You didn't tell me about Humpty.
所以你欠我两次了
So now you owe me two.
- 你真是难对付 - 对啊 但我值得嘛
- You're a lot of work. - I know. But I am worth it!
你跑不掉的 穿靴子的猫!
You are not getting away, Puss In Boots!
烂靴子
Wrong boots.
咪!
Kitty!
现在扯平了!
Now we're even!
这里是圣里卡多天气预报
This is your San Ricardo weather report.
一只巨鹅毁掉这镇子的几率是...
Chances of a giant goose destroying the town...
百分之百
...one hundred percent.
永不落单 团结一致
Never alone, always together...
矮蛋和猫...
Humpty and Puss...
永是兄弟
Brothers forever.
来吧 宝贝 在妈妈来之前离开这里吧
Come on, sweetie. Let's, uh, get out of here before Mama shows up.
我该煎了你做鸡蛋沙拉三明治!
I should make you into an egg salad sandwich!
这太恶心了!
That is disgusting!
给我金鹅 矮蛋
Give me the goose, Humpty.
这恐怕做不到
No can do, I'm afraid.
看 她妈妈就要来了 而当她来了之后...
See, the mama's on her way, and when she gets here,
圣里卡多和你在乎的一切都要拜拜了
it's bye-bye San Ricardo and everything you ever cared about!
对我复仇是一回事 那伊梅尔达呢? 孤儿院呢?
Revenge on me is one thing, but why Imelda? Why the orphanage?
那是我们的家啊
This is our home.
你是说你家
You mean your home.
我根本不属于这里
I never belonged here.
我们本来计划好逃走的
We had a plan to get out of here,
但突然间英雄出现了 然后选择了这里而抛弃了我
but then you became a hero and you picked this place over me.
你带走了我的一切
You left me with nothing.
矮蛋 很抱歉我伤害了你
Humpty... I'm sorry I hurt you.
但不要牵连这里的人 你不是这样的人!
But do not take it out on these people. You are better than this!
- 不 我是的 - 哦 拜托 !
- No, I'm not. - Oh, come on!
我认识真正的矮蛋
I know the real Humpty.
那不平凡的眼光 那位发明家 那位梦想家
The way you saw the world! The inventor! The dreamer!
那个人怎么了?
What happened to that guy?
我...我想已经太晚了
I... I think it's too late.
做正确的事情永远不晚
It is never too late to do the right thing.
我们在一起 能拯救圣里卡多
Together we can save San Ricardo!
我这就原谅你 矮蛋 只要你帮我一把
I can forgive you, Humpty... if you help me now.
真的?
Really?
在我对你做过这么多事情之后?
After everything I put you through?
这就证明给我看 你有颗闪亮的心
Prove to me there is still a good egg in you.
我会努力的
I'll try.
眼镜好了
Goggles, check.
把小鹅带到桥那里 我会把妈妈带过去
Get the baby over the bridge. I'll get the mother to follow.
好 帮我...
OK. Give me a...
猫!
Puss!
鹅妈妈!
Mama Goose!
等等!
Wait!
跟我走 我能帮你找到宝宝
Just follow me and I will lead you to your baby.
不! 不是那边!
No! Not that way!
我的孩子 救命啊!
Pequeno, help!
撑住!
Hang on!
那是我的孩子
That's my boy!
跟我来 鹅妈妈 我知道你的宝宝在哪儿
Come with me, Mama Goose. I know where your baby is.
这边 看啊!
Here. Look!
矮蛋 快马加鞭!
Humpty, pick up the pace!
我在努力 猫! 我在努力!
I'm trying, Puss! I'm trying!
抱歉 蛋头 我们想要的不止金蛋
Sorry, egghead, we want more than just eggs.
把金鹅给我们怎样?
So how about you give us that goose!
矮蛋!
Humpty!
让她走开!
Get her off!
- 干的漂亮 - 没有我你能干什么?
- Nice moves. - What would you do without me?
站住!
Freeze!
卫队长!
Comandante!
我能解释?
I can explain?
猫!我一定要把你送回牢房! 我这辈子一定要抓住你!
Gato, you are going back to jail if it's the last thing I do!
矮蛋 快啊!
Humpty, hurry!
我们快到了 我们快到了!
We're almost there. We're almost there!
- 救命 猫! - 矮蛋 撑住!
- Puss, help! - Humpty, hang on!
猫!
Puss!
又这样了 对吧 猫?
Here we are again, right, Puss?
我这次绝不放手 矮蛋
I will not leave you behind this time, Humpty.
对不起 猫
I'm sorry, Puss.
我总是做不好事情
I've made a mess out of everything.
我是颗坏蛋
I'm a rotten egg.
我不是人类
I'm not a person.
我也不是鸟类 我还不能吃
I'm not a bird. I'm not even a food.
我连自己是什么都不知道
I don't know what I am.
你就是 永远都是
You are what you have always been.
我的兄弟
My brother.
永远的兄弟
Brothers forever.
- 你无法同时救我们俩 - 不 我能 撑住就好
- You can't save us both. - Yes, I can! Just hang on!
猫 你必须要救鹅宝宝 不然鹅妈妈会毁了圣里卡多
Puss, you have to save the baby, or the mama will destroy San Ricardo.
这样做才对
It's the right thing to do.
这次我不会放手的 矮蛋
I will not let you go, Humpty.
我知道你不会
I know you won't.
所以我让你别无选择
So I won't make you choose.
矮蛋!
Humpty!
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
她没事了
She's OK.
矮蛋?
Humpty?
我就知道你内心闪亮
I always knew that you were good inside.
再见 矮蛋
Goodbye, Humpty.
- 是啊 我认为那非常精彩... - 我得到了一颗鹅蛋
- Yeah, I think it's wonderful... - And I got a goose egg.
是他 穿靴子的猫
It's him. Puss In Boots.
他从巨鹅手中解救了我们
He saved us from the giant goose!
他的剑犹如闪电
His sword is like lightning!
他们说他有十条命
They say he has ten lives.
他的靴子是用最上乘的皮做
His boots are made of the finest Corinthian leather.
他只喝牛奶
He only drinks whole milk.
好传说
Good leche.
他不是法外之徒 他救了我们!
He's no outlaw. He saved us!
喵...
meow?
给你的礼物 妈妈
A gift for you, Mama.
我要走了 卫兵要来抓我了
I have to go. The soldiers are coming for me.
我真为你骄傲 孩子
I am so proud of you, my son.
今天 你以勇气和荣耀面对过去
Today, you faced the past with bravery and honor.
你赢得了这双靴子
You earned those boots.
而人们都知道你是圣里卡多最伟大的英雄
And the people know that you are San Ricardo's greatest hero.
为你而做的 妈妈
I did it for you, Mama.
你会一直在我心里
You will always be in my heart.
你也在我心里
And you in mine.
猫!
iGato!
- 在那儿! - 我看到他了!
- There he is! - I see him!
我们会再见的 咪・柔爪
I will see you again, Kitty Softpaws!
而且很快哦
Sooner than you think.
她真是只坏猫咪
She is a bad kitty.
这是一只猫 变成英雄的故事
This is the story of a cat who became a hero.
一个维护正义的法外之徒 一个怜香惜玉的人
An outlaw dedicated to justice. And a lover of beautiful women.
一个伟大的 伟大的爱人
A great... great lover.
真的 我很疯狂
Really. It is crazy.
我是穿靴子的猫
I am Puss In Boots!
而我的名字将成为传奇
And my name would become... legend!
穿靴子的猫
喵...
Meow.